PEDRO MARTINS GRAPHIC DESIGNER

PERSONAL STATEMENT

Graphic Designer based in the UK with expertise ranging from web design, HTML/CSS coding, printing, packaging, UX, email marketing and more. My design philosophy is always aimed at expressing the message over everything whilst also interrogating the brief to its fullest.

INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

2022-Present | Graphic Designer (LilaConnect)

Working as the sole designer for the company, whilst taking on the role of dedicated brand master. Key responsibilities include the design and quality assurance of all print & digital marketing material, overseeing the work produced by external parties on behalf of company, and presenting marketing campaign concepts to internal & external stakeholders.

2021–2022 | Graphic Designer (Core Creative Limited)

Working in a digital marketing agency designing digital and print assets whilst also undertaking the roles of marketing and project manager for clients. Key responsibilities involve creating monthly campaigns, designing email marketing, packaging, building HTML emails, and managing client projects under tight deadlines.

2017-2021 | Freelance Designer

Designing for clients has enabled me to work efficiently on multiple projects at once, whilst guiding the client through the process to a finished and functional product. Key projects include WordPress sites, logos & branding, UX & UI designs, and a presentation for the NHS.

EDUCATION

2016–2019 | University of Reading

Bachelor of Arts, Graphic Communication: 2:1

Studying here gave me an appreciation for typography, undertaking briefs within various design sectors, and further expand my skills set. Key skills learned include Adobe software, clientele communication, research based design, pitch presentations, and UX design.

2013–2016 | Cornwall College, St Austell

Level 3 Foundation Diploma in Art & Design: DistinctionFurther study into preparing for the creative industry. Final project involved a series of posters which went on to win CreateEd in 2016.

A-Level Art & Design: Graphic Communication: A (a)

Working within an appropriate studie studying Design mayone

Working within an open design studio studying Design movements, Branding, Book design, Poster design, and Adobe software.

BTEC Level 3 Extended Diploma BUSINESS (QCF): D*DD

Researching current business practices, gaining a deep understanding on Marketing, Finances, Advertising, Corporate, and Business structures.

ACADEMIC ACHIEVEMENTS

June 2016 | Certificate of Excellence: Graphic Design
Falmouth University hosted
CreatEd 2016, an event aimed towards showcasing GCSE and A-level work across Cornwall, where I received the Certificate of Excellence for winning my category (Graphic Design).

SOFTWARE SKILLS

Adobe Photoshop

Adobe InDesign

Adobe Illustrator

Microsoft Office

Adobe After Effects

HTML + CSS

JavaScript

DESIGN SKILLS

Branding design / Typography / Logo design / Poster design / Web design / Design for print / Packaging / UI & UX design / Marketing / Editorial design / Email campaigns / Letterpress

HOBBIES & INTERESTS



